answerthepublic.com 2019-11-22

# AnswerThePublic: that free visual keyword research & content ideas tool

### ANSWERTHEPUBLIC PRIVACY POLICY

We are committed to protecting and respecting privacy. This Privacy Policy should be read in conjunction with our Terms and Conditions and applies to your use of our Site. The same definitions apply.

**INTRODUCTION:** Personal data is information that allows someone to identify or contact you e.g. your name, address, telephone number, email address, as well as any other information about you that is associated or linked to such information (‘your Information’). This Privacy Policy sets out the basis on which we may collect, use, process and store your Information that we collect or that you provide to us by any direct or indirect means. Please read the relevant sections of our Site when you submit any Information to us. This Privacy Policy explains our practices regarding your Information and how we will treat it. By submitting any of your Information to us through either our Site or otherwise, you are agreeing to the terms of this Privacy Policy. You expressly consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy and you represent and warrant that you have all rights necessary to submit your Information. Please do not submit to us any personal data relating to you or any other data subject unless you have the right to do so.

**HELP:** If you need any help or assistance in relation to the use of our Site, please contact support@answerthepublic.com and we will do our best to get back to you promptly.

**INFORMATION WE MAY COLLECT FROM YOU:** We may collect and process the following Information about you: 

  * Information that you provide or input when you subscribe and use the Site, when you fill out forms on our Site and otherwise by corresponding with us or interacting with us via or in connection with our Site.
  * Contact details that you provide to us.
  * Any documents, content, communications and electronic files that you upload or import to or transmit through our Site.
  * Information that you permit us to access and import from third party websites or storage locations.
  * If you contact us or we contact you, by email, telephone, web forms or otherwise, we may keep a record of that correspondence.
  * We may also ask you to complete surveys that we use for research purposes, although you do not have to respond to them.
  * Details of your visits to our Site including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs, and other communication data, and the resources that you access.
  * When you access our Site from a computer, mobile phone, or other device, we may collect information from that device about your browser type, location, and IP address etc.
  * Searches that you perform via the Site (therefore, be aware of this if you include any personally identifiable information in your searches).

**IP ADDRESSES, COOKIES AND ANALYTICS:** Our servers may collect your Information including data about your computer or device, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type, to assist us in the provision of the Site, for system administration and to report aggregate anonymised information to our associates and third party contractors.

For the same reason, we may obtain your Information about Site usage by using a cookie file which is stored on the hard drive of your computer. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive. They help us to improve our Site and to deliver a better and more personalised service. They enable us: 

  * To make our Site more useful to you.
  * To estimate our audience size and usage patterns.
  * To store your Information about preferences, and so allow us to customise and develop our Site.
  * To speed up your searches and usage of the Site.
  * To recognise you when you return to our Site.

You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of cookies. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our Site. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you start using our Site. 

We may also collect or allow third parties to collect information about how you use and interact with our Site. For example, we may use Google Analytics or similar services. 

**HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION:** We use your Information in the following ways: 

  * As reasonably required in order to provide our Site to you and to carry out our obligations arising from our Site.
  * To help identify you as a user on our systems
  * For customer services purposes.
  * To help us develop the Site and to make them more useful to you.
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of our Site.
  * To provide you with news and information about our Site, third party sites and other information that we think may be relevant to you.
  * To assist our third party contractors to monitor end user usage of their third party services provided via the Site.
  * To ensure that content from our Site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer.
  * Where directed to by you through our Site, to export your Information in order to update or delete your Information and/or add to or amend your Information held on a third party website or to carry out any other similar function.
  * To notify you about changes to our Site.
  * As required in order to facilitate your use of any new features on the Site, applications or uses for any of your Information via our Site.

**LEGAL BASIS OF PROCESSING:** We shall only be entitled to process your Information as above to the extent that at least one of the following applies: 

  * You have given consent to the processing of your Information for one or more specific purposes;
  * Processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are party or to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract;
  * Processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject;
  * Processing is necessary in order to protect your vital interests or those of another natural person;
  * Processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest of in the exercise of official authority vested in the controller;

Processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by us or by a third party, except where such interests are overridden by the interests of your fundamental rights and freedoms which require protection of personal data. Our legitimate interests may include: 

  * The proper administration of our Site;
  * The performance of our contractual obligations;
  * Monitoring and improving our Site;
  * Taking steps at your request;
  * Communicating with users of our Site;
  * The protection and assertion of legal rights;
  * The protection of our business against risks.

**DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION:** We may disclose your Information subject to the same restrictions as contained in this Privacy Policy to any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 736 of the UK Companies Act 1985. We may also disclose your Information to third parties: 

  * When we subcontract the running of our Site or any part of it to a third party or where the Site interacts with a third party service provider, provided that all subcontractors are bound by reasonable privacy policies.
  * In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your Information in confidence to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.
  * If we or substantially all of our assets are transferred to or acquired by a third party, in which case all of your Information will be one of the transferred assets on the equivalent terms and conditions as herein.
  * If we are under a duty to disclose or share your Information in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our terms and conditions other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of us, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging Information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

**RETENTION OF YOUR INFORMATION:** We will endeavour not keep your Information for longer than necessary in order to facilitate your use of our Site. If you wish to delete your Pro Plan subscription, we will delete the content we hold in relation to you on request, except that some prior content may remain in backup or cached copies for a reasonable time (but we will not make it available again to third parties). In addition, content that you have submitted to our third party contractors may still be in use and so there may be some ongoing use of your Information. We may also retain certain information to prevent identity theft, legal disputes and misconduct, even if deletion has been requested.

**THIRD PARTY CONTRACTORS:** All of your Information that you provide to us is stored on our servers, which may be hosted by third parties. Any payment transactions (if any) will be encrypted and may be processed by third party payment providers.

**THIRD PARTY WEBSITES:** When you click on a link to a third party website, you will leave our Site and a third party may collect your Information from that site subject to their own privacy policy. We have no control over such third party sites and privacy policies. This Privacy Policy only applies to your Information collected by us via this Site.

**WHERE WE STORE AND PROCESS YOUR INFORMATION:** Your Information that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by third parties and staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers as necessary for operating the Site. If any processing of your Information is to take place outside of the EEA in a third country or international organisation which does not ensure an adequate level of data protection, we may only transfer your Information if appropriate safeguards have been implemented and on the condition that enforceable data subject rights and effective legal remedies for data subjects are available. The safeguards may be by way of EU Model Contract Clauses, binding corporate rules, approved code of conduct or approved certification mechanism. If you require any further information in this regard, please contact support@answerthepublic.com.

**ANONYMOUS DATA:** We may create anonymous records from your Information by excluding all data from which you may be identified or contacted. We may use such anonymised data for our reasonable business purposes (including but not limited to research and develop our Site and our business).

**YOUR RIGHTS:** You have a number of rights as a data subject as summarised below: 

  * **ACCESS:** You have the right to obtain confirmation as to whether or not personal data concerning you are being processed and, where that is the case, to access your Information and details of how we process it, as long as this does not adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others. You may request a copy of Information undergoing processing, subject to evidence of your identity (normally a certified copy of your passport plus an original copy of a utility bill showing your current address). The first copy shall be provided without charge, but reasonable administration fees shall be charged for additional or subsequent copies.
  * **RECTIFICATION:** We will rectify any errors in the Information we hold on request.
  * **ERASURE:** You may erase your Information from our systems in the following situations: 
    * The Information is no longer necessary in relation to the purpose for which it was collected;
    * You withdraw your consent on which the processing is based and where there is no other legal ground for the processing;
    * You object to the processing and there are no overriding legitimate grounds for the processing;
    * The Information has been unlawfully processed;
    * The Information has to be erased for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject.
  * **RIGHT TO RESTRICTION OF PROCESSING:** You have the right to restrict our processing on specified grounds.
  * **NOTIFICATION:** Where you have asked us to rectify, erase or restrict processing of your information, we shall communicate the same to each recipient to whom your Information has been disclosed, unless this proves impossible or involves disproportionate effort, in which case we shall let you know.
  * **DATA PORTABILITY:** You have the right in specific circumstances where processing is based on consent to receive your Information in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and have the right to transmit the Information to another controller without hindrance, provided that our processing is carried out by automated means.
  * **RIGHT TO OBJECT:** In certain circumstances you have the right to object to our processing of your Information, including in relation to profiling, direct marketing or scientific or historical research purposes.
  * **AUTOMATED INDIVIDUAL DECISION MAKING:** You have the right not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling, which produces legal effects concerning you unless this is necessary for our contract, is authorised under applicable law or is based on your explicit consent.

You can exercise these right by contacting us at support@answerthepublic.com and/or by following our online account procedures. We shall respond to your requests without undue delay and in any event within one month unless we need to extend such period by up to two further months in specific circumstances. Please note that if you delete or restrict your account or required Information, this may prevent you from making full use of our Site.

**SECURITY:** Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our Site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone, including people who work for us.

The transmission of you Information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your Information, we cannot guarantee the security of your Information transmitted to or from our Site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your Information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

LAST UPDATED APRIL 2018
